<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on ingxfm</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on ingxfm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.136.1</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2024</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:29:10 +0201</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spectacle: How to report a KDE bug?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/spectacle_bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 18:29:10 +0201</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/spectacle_bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, le moi was writing his Friday article. This poor soul needed a few screenshots and lo and behold his Spectacle tool presented a not so spectacular behavior. Spectacle required the following actions to make one screenshot: open Spectacle -&amp;gt; Area: Rectangular Region -&amp;gt; click on Take a New Screenshot, the mouse pointer disappears, then open again Spectacle from Super -&amp;gt; click again Take a New Screenshot, then I can see the pointer normally. So, for the price of 2 screenshots I got one. Makes sense since we are near the November&amp;rsquo;s black Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hobbies for engineers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/hobbies_for_engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 11:01:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/hobbies_for_engineers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you work as an engineer and want to pick a hobby so that you can put in practice outside of work some of the math, natural and/or social science principles you have learned? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at some nice hobby ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cars&#34;&gt;Cars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many possibilities related to these vehicles. What about getting involved in the maintenance of the car? What about some modifications to the headlights, or the suspensions?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spaced repetition, forgetting curve and Anki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/anki_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 21:56:43 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/anki_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever studied a new material, and have forgotten almost immediately after using it (for work, or for an exam)? Have you ever forgotten something you thought you had understood well? Are you trying to learn a new language and forget the new vocabulary all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that happens to me, as well. You are not alone. In my case, I have found a solution in the form of a technique, the so-called spaced repetition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux command Tail: useful for monitoring log text files</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tail_linux_ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 08:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/tail_linux_ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When monitoring any program logs in Ubuntu or in many Linux based operating systems one can use the tail command. The tail command outputs the last lines of a text file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the command in the shell program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;Shell&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;tail /&amp;lt;path&amp;gt;/logfile.log
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;By default, the tail command will show the last 10 lines. If you want to specify the number of lines, enter the command with the flag &amp;ldquo;-n&amp;rdquo;, in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hood&#39;s everyday life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/vida_cotidiana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 06:11:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/vida_cotidiana/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday life in the hood is so much better when we tamper down our hormones. I have tested it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to live in a hood where normal everyday people would throw trash anywhere. Furthermore, they would blast their music at eardrum-damaging volume. Moreover, you were always worried someone was going to ask you with a lack of courtesy to hand him over the nice looking belongings you were carrying, even midday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to read a Book by Mortimer Adler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/how_to_read_a_book_ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 18:54:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/blog/how_to_read_a_book_ma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a book close to my heart because it dawned on me how below average one can act. In my search for being less stupid, I read “How to read a book by Mortimer Adler and Charles Van Doren (edition 1972)”. Let&amp;rsquo;s call this book HRB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a practical How-to book that explains how to read better if our goal is lifting our mind from understanding less to understanding more, to knowing more about life, the world, and ourselves. “Know thyself” someone said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
